Rui Dantas

Full Stack Developer

Toronto, Ontario • (647) 237-8213 • ruidantas55@gmail.com • Github • LinkedIn • Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a passion for Front-end Development. Through my years of working as a self-taught freelance Creative Director, Photographer/Videographer, and Graphic designer in the music industry, I was able to build the work ethic, problem-solving skills, and teamwork skills needed to strive in such industries. Through a strong process of research, planning, design, development, and testing, I am able to create a fully functioning web application that meets the needs of clients.

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, EJS, NextJS, TypeScript

Libraries & Frameworks: React, React Router, Express, Nodejs, jQuery, Tailwind, Axios

Database: PostgreSQL

Software: Photoshop, Lightroom, After Effects, Premier Pro, Figma, Blender

PROJECTS

Card Heroes - Full Stack Developer

Feb 2023

Card Heroes is the ultimate destination for trading card enthusiasts. With over a million cards to choose from, we have the perfect card for every collector.

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JS, EJS, SASS Backend: Node, Express, PostgreSQL

Talento - Full Stack Developer

Jan 2023

Talento is a revolutionary job search platform that leverages the swipe mechanic from popular dating apps to streamline the job hunting process for both employers and job seekers.

Frontend: HTML, CSS, SASS

Backend: Node, Express, PostgreSQL

Scheduler - Front End Engineer

Mar 2023

React-based project to create meetings for students to connect with mentors in real time.

Frontend: React, Axios, Classnames, Normalize, Storybook

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs - Diploma: Full Stack Web Development
Chaminade College - High School Diploma

Oct 2022 - May 2023

Sep 2012 - June 2016

EXPERIENCE

Creative Director - Sept. 2016 to Current - Los Angeles/Toronto

- **Develop and execute creative vision**: Develop and execute the creative vision for an Artist. This involves working closely with the musician to understand their goals and objectives and then developing a strategy for achieving those goals through innovative and compelling creative content.
- Lead and manage a team of 5-10 creative individuals: Providing direction, feedback, and guidance on creative projects, as well as ensuring that all work is completed on time and within budget.
- **Collaborate with cross-functional teams**: Ensure that all creative content is aligned with the overall brand and messaging by collaborating with graphic designers, videographers, stylists, etc. We worked together to ensure that our vision supports the goals and objectives of the artist.

Photographer / Videographer & Graphic Designer - Apr. 2017 to Current - Los Angeles/Toronto

- Capture and edit visual content: Capture and edit visual content, including photos, videos, and graphics, for use in various mediums such as websites, social media, and marketing materials.
- Collaborate with clients: Collaborate with clients to understand their vision and goals, and then develop a
 strategy for capturing and creating visual content that aligns with the overall vision and that it supports the goals
 and objectives of the artist.